Patrick Cunningham

Data Analyst | Training Organizer

(615)715-0775 | pcunningham1489@yahoo.com | www.linkedin.com/in/patrickcunningham-cui-weiyi | https://github.com/Cuiweiyi

ABOUT ME

Proficient in Mandarin Chinese, having studied abroad in Zhanghua, Taiwan and lived for 2 years in Wuhan, China. Worked in training and technical troubleshooting previously. During the 2020 pandemic I decided to challenge myself by attempting the most difficult skill I could think of, which was coding. I found I liked it through free code camp, which led me to enroll in Nashville Software School. I enjoy the challenge

SKILLS

- Python (pandas)
- Power BI
- Git/GitHub
- Leadership and Management

- Conflict resolution
- Tableau
- SQL (PostgreSQL)

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYTICS | NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | JAN 2021 - PRESENT

1-2 sentence description/summary of NSS

PROJECTS

• City-Cemetery-Burials(Excel): Uses Excel to look at various metrics of historic Nashville cemetery and present. Data initially dirty, was cleaned up and sorted by ages and causes of death. This was a group project.

(https://github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohorts-6/city-cemetery-burials-Cuiweiyi/blob/main/Historic_City_Cemetery.xlsx)

 Tableau-workshop (Tableau): Screwtape Letters parody based off of downloaded app data for iPhone. Pulled data and renamed data for pivot tables with an interactive slicer, had adaptable graphs and hidden sections for selective focus.

(https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/patrick.cunningham3688/viz/TableauScrewtabpLetter/Real_Dash?public =ves)

• gdp-and-internet-usage (Python 3): Looks into GDP data by country and compares internet usage using Python 3.4 and Jupyter Notebooks. After cleaning and merging the data I was able to make charts comparing and contrasting the countries with highest GDP and highest internet usage to those with the lowest. (https://github.com/NSS-Data-Analytics-Cohort-6/gdp-and-internet-usage-

Cuiweiyi/blob/main/notebooks/Setup%20for%20the%20gdp_percap.ipynb_)

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Analytics or Science Bootcamp Certification | Nashville Software School | projected graduation: 06/28/22
- Bachelor of Science in Interdisciplinary Studies | Austin Peay University | 12/2012
- HSK (Hanyu Shuiping Kaoshi) level 3 Chinese proficiency test

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Phi Alpha Theta: honors history fraternity, (08/2012 to present)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CSO 3 | Vanderbilt University | 03/2016 - present

Vanderbilt Public Security has sworn police officers that provide security for the Vanderbilt community. As a CSO 3 I am in the training department and taught OC, Ethics, Customer Service, and Field Training.

- Assist in community relations via outreach, and interactions between the community and VUPS. I
 specifically led training classes and put together a liaison program to reach international students and
 address their concerns
- Training personnel and schedule organizer
- Conflict resolution through de-escalation tactics and methods as taught by POST certifications

Armed security | APEX Security | 09/2014-2016

APEX is a security company that partners with businesses to provide guards at events and locations.

- Conducted area checks of assigned zones
- Conflict resolution with upset and/or interacting parties
- Community service and interactions with directions, aid, and security

English Teacher | Wuhan Institute of Technology | 02/2013-2014

Wuhan Institute of Technology is a college on the outskirts of Wuchang. Routinely foreign teachers to instruct in fluency.

- Developed, organized, and implemented syllabus to achieve strategic teaching goals -Evaluated and taught oral English skills as well as written journals
- Led lectures, discussions, and activities including English corner an impromptu gathering of students